▍2026 美网 女单 16 强
郑钦文 7-5 6-3 斯瓦泰克 · 赛后新闻发布会
up in the first set.
在第一盘领先的时候
Did you feel like you got
你有没有觉得自己
a little bit more tense or a little bit ahead
有点紧张 或者有点
of yourself?
想得太早了？
Just kind of what do you think led
你觉得是什么导致了
to that, you know, come back?
她那一波反扑？
Honestly, no.
说实话 没有
For sure I felt like I started missing too
我确实觉得自己开始失误
many shots.
太多了
She started playing in.
她开始把球打进来了
I let her back into into the match.
是我让她回到了比赛里
So, no, but I honestly my focus
所以不是 说实话我的专注
was the same as always.
和平时一样
I wanted to play the same as always.
我想打得和平时一样
Just starting to started to miss too much.
只是开始失误太多
wanted to adjust it,
我想调整
but nothing kind of worked at at that point.
但那时候怎么调都不管用
And I knew I'm going
而且我知道我还会
to have, you know,
有
another chance and I wanted to use it,
别的机会 我也想抓住
but I missed them all.
但我一个都没兑现
Eva,
伊娃 请问
hey, tough luck today,
今天运气不太好
but when you're when you're up 5-1
但当你 5-1 领先的时候
and you do have that cushion,
你手上有足够的缓冲
h how what kind of mental adjustment
那你要做什么样的心理调整
do you have to make of like it feels like you
就是感觉你明明
have a lot of time to get things back
有很多时间把局面拉回来
and then all of a sudden like
然后突然之间
you don't have time?
你就没时间了？
I never judge that I'm going to have a lot
我从不觉得自己会有
of time.
很多时间
That's why I usually am able to close
所以我通常能用
the sets with a pretty straightforward score.
很直接的比分收下一盘
Because I'm good
因为我擅长
at like I don't know like even imagining
怎么说呢 就是去想象
that the score line is is not like
比分并不是
that and just pushing
那样 然后一直往前顶
and being intense all the time.
全程都保持强度
But like today I I wouldn't say it
但今天我不会说
had anything to do with mentality.
这跟心态有什么关系
It was more that I started making mistakes,
更多是我开始失误
you know, from easy balls
从很简单的球开始
and Qinwen stopped, you know,
而郑钦文
doing doing mistakes.
不再失误了
She she played the balls better
她把球处理得更好
and yeah,
就是这样
Matt.
马特 请问
Hey, tough one.
今天这场挺难的
I know New York doesn't necessarily
我知道纽约不一定
like fit with you.
很适合你
you can find ita chaotic and noisy
你可能觉得这里又乱又吵
and things like that.
之类的
How was your comfort level here
这十天你在这里
during the past 10 days
待得舒不舒服
or so or two weeks really?
或者说这两周
I think it's chaotic for everyone.
我觉得对所有人都是乱的
So you just need to deal with it
你只需要去应付它
and I've been fine.
我一直挺好
Thank
谢谢
eager. I remember you saying
下一位 我记得你说过
at Roland Garros that you felt very tense
你在法网说过在场上很紧张
on court and it's been a bit stressful
而且最近这几个月
being on the tennis tour in recent months.
打巡回赛压力有点大
Have you felt that here at all
你在这里有过这种感觉吗
or do you feel you've moved on from that?
还是你觉得已经走出来了？
Yeah, I feel like I moved on.
是 我觉得我走出来了
For sure it's not so easy for me
这里对我来说确实
to play here as on a bit slower surface
不如慢一点的场地好打
where the ball is bouncing a bit higher.
就是球弹得高一些的那种
But you know still I feel like I could have
但我还是觉得我本可以
played a bit better so that's unfortunate.
打得更好一点 挺可惜的
But I feel like for sure this part
不过我觉得这一段赛季
of the season has been better in terms
在这方面
of managing that.
确实处理得更好了
So, yeah.
就是这样
Exactly.
好的
What experiences in your career, if any,
你职业生涯里有没有
have been comparable to this and how
类似的经历 那时候你
did you go about bouncing back
是怎么重新振作
from those?
起来的？
Honestly, every US Open except 2022
说实话 除了 2022 年
has been like that.
每一届美网都是这样
So, many like we face many losses.
我们要面对很多次失利
So obviously it's not the best thing
这话说出来可能
to say, but like in tennis you're more used
不太好听 但打网球
to losing than winning.
你习惯输多过习惯赢
So I don't feel like I need
所以我不觉得我需要
to like bounce back from anything.
从什么里面走出来
Just need to focus on the work
只需要专心准备
before next tournament
下一站之前的训练
and there are going to be other chances
以后还会有别的机会
to play good tennis and I'll focus
打出好网球 我会专注于
on growing and developing my game
让自己的球继续长
and that's it.
就这样
I was speaking more specifically
我问的其实更具体
about the first set having been up five love
是第一盘 5-0 领先那件事
and bouncing back from that.
以及从那里面走出来
How do you think you'll go
你觉得你会怎么
about internalizing that and growing
消化它 并且从中
from it?
成长起来？
It's just one match like I'll try
就是一场球而已 我会
to play the same way as usual.
照平时那样去打
What do you mean? Like
你什么意思？
do you think it's something crazy?
你觉得这有什么了不得吗？
you know, you can lose a set
任何比分下
from any score.
你都可能丢掉一盘
So, nothing special about that.
所以这没什么特别的
Just that's what happened and that's it.
就是这么发生了 仅此而已
Okay, last question.
好 最后一个问题
English.
用英语
Tammani, just curious.
请问 我就是好奇
You took a medical time out
你叫了一次医疗暂停
and how are you feeling physically?
身体感觉怎么样？
Well, I've been fresher, but just little,
我也有过更精神的时候
you know, my quad is quite tired,
我的股四头肌很累
but it had no influence on the game.
但它对比赛没有影响
just wanted to, you know,
我只是想
give it a little boost, but yeah,
给它提一提劲
it didn't influence anything.
它没有影响到任何事
It seemed like you've
看起来你一直
been problem solving very well on court
很擅长在场上解决问题
and you know, finding solutions.
总能找到办法
So, it did it feel kind of different today
那今天是不是不太一样
that you weren't able to find a solution?
因为你没能找到办法？
Well, I was just mishitting the balls,
我就是没打到甜点
you know.
你知道的
So, didn't feel like I had space
所以我觉得没有空间
to to feel it better.
去把球感找回来
I don't know.
我也说不好
Um,
嗯
well, I framed a lot.
我打到拍框上很多次
I didn't hit the ball in the right place.
我没把球打在对的位置上
It's not so easy
而且不太容易
to adjust like the basic things in the game
去调整比赛里最基本的东西
if they're not working, you know.
如果它们本来就不管用
Just try to focus
只能尽量让自己专注
on having like smooth rhythm
保持流畅的节奏
and everything, but also, you know,
这些东西 但同时
I was not I didn't have a good timing.
我的时机感也不好
I wasn't hitting the ball right.
我没有把球打实
So, it's tough to get
所以很难
over that when when it happens.
在这种时候熬过去
And maybe I could have
也许我本可以
played more safe or something,
打得更保守一些
but I also didn't feel like I have space
但我也觉得面对郑钦文
with Qinwen to do that.
我没有那个余地
If I would be more solid
如果我能比她更稳
than her, I would win this game,
我就赢下这场球了
but I wasn't solid
但我不够稳
and I was missing too much.
我失误太多
So, yeah, had like some ideas of what
我确实有过一些想法
to do with it.
想怎么去处理它